<resources>
    <string name="app_name">Garden Encyclopedia</string>

    <string name="navigation_drawer_open">Open navigation drawer</string>
    <string name="navigation_drawer_closed">Closed navigation drawer</string>

    <string name="planting_cabbage">
        <b><big>PLANTING</big></b>\n
        \n<li>Start cabbage seeds indoors 6 to 8 weeks before the last spring frost.</li>
        \n<li>Harden off plants over the course of a week. To prepare soil, till in aged manure or compost.</li>
        \n<li>Transplant outdoors 2 to 3 weeks before the last expected frost date. Choose a cloudy afternoon.</li>
        \n<li>Plant 12 to 24 inches apart in rows, depending on size of head desired. The closer you plant, the smaller the heads.</li>
        \n<li>Mulch thickly to retain moisture and regulate soil temperature.</li>
        \n<li>Practice crop rotation with cabbage year to year to avoid a buildup of soil borne diseases.</li>
        \n<li>Because cabbage, broccoli, and cauliflower are closely related, and require similar nutrients, it’s best not to plant them together. They are all heavy feeders, depleting the soil faster of required nutrients; plus, they will attract the same pests and diseases. For cabbage, also avoid proximity to strawberries and tomatoes.</li>
        \n<li>Cabbage can be grown near beans and cucumbers.</li>
        \n<li>Check out our chart of plant companions for an expanded list of friends and foes.</li>
    </string>
    <string name="care_cabbage">
        <b><big>CARE</big></b>\n
        \n<li>When transplants reach 5 inches tall, thin to make sure they are still the desired length apart. (The plants you remove can be transplanted elsewhere in your garden.)</li>
        \n<li>Fertilize 3 weeks after transplanting.</li>
        \n<li>Keep soil moist with mulch and water 2 inches per week.</li>
    </string>
    <string name="pests_cabbage">
        <b><big>PESTS/DISEASES</big></b>\n
        \n<li>Imported Cabbageworms</li>
        \n<li>Aphids</li>
        \n<li>Cabbage Root Maggots</li>
        \n<li>Flea Beetles</li>
        \n<li>Cutworms</li>
        \n<li>Splitting</li>
    </string>
    <string name="harvest_cabbage">
        <b><big>HARVEST/STORAGE</big></b>\n
        \n<li>Harvest when heads reach desired size and are firm. This will take around 70 days for most green cabbage varieties. Most early varieties will produce 1- to 3-pound heads.</li>
        \n<li>Cut each cabbage head at its base with a sharp knife. After harvesting, bring inside or put in shade immediately.</li>
        \n<li>To get two crops from early cabbage plants, cut the cabbage head out of the plant, leaving the outer leaves and root in the garden. The plant will send up new heads—pinch them off until only four or so smaller heads remain. When these grow to tennis-ball size, they’ll be perfect for salad.</li>
        \n<li>After harvesting, remove the entire stem and root system from the soil to prevent disease buildup. Only compost healthy plants; destroy those with maggot infestation.</li>
        \n<li>Cabbage can be stored in the refrigerator for no more than two weeks, wrapped lightly in plastic. Make sure it is dry before storing. In proper root cellar conditions, cabbage will keep for up to 3 months.</li>
    </string>

    <string name="planting_blueberries">
        <b><big>PLANTING</big></b>\n
        \n<li>Select a sunny, sheltered spot. While blueberries are tolerant of shade, better crops are obtained in the sun.</li>
        \n<li>Blueberries thrive in soil that is acidic. The soil pH should ideally be between 4 and 5. Soil can be acidified by mixing a small amount of granulated sulfur into the soil several months before planting. Peat moss, as well as pine bark or needles, are also good additions that will help acidify your soil.</li>
        \n<li>The blueberry is a shallow-rooted plant. Therefore, it requires a soil that holds moisture, but also drains well and doesn’t stay wet.</li>
        \n<li>Mix organic matter into the soil before you set your blueberry bushes.</li>
        \n<li>Bushes should be planted as early in the spring as possible. If available, 1- to 3-year-old plants are a good choice. Be sure to go to a reputable nursery. </li>
        \n<li>Dig holes about 20 inches deep and 18 inches wide (about twice as wide and twice as deep as the roots of the plant).</li>
        \n<li>Space bushes about 5 feet apart in a row, with at least 8 feet between rows. Prepare a planting mixture of 2 parts loam and one part oak leaf mold, peat moss, aged sawdust, or compost, and place a layer of this mixture in the bottom of the hole.</li>
        \n<li>Set the bush in the hole with its roots spread out. Don’t plant the bush any deeper than it grew in the pot. Pack the hole tightly with soil.</li>
        \n<li>Apply fertilizer one month after planting, not at the time of planting. Apply ½ ounce of a 10-10-10 fertilizer in a band around the plant 6 to 12 inches from the crown.</li>
    </string>
    <string name="care_blueberries">
        <b><big>CARE</big></b>\n
        \n<li>Mulch to keep shallow blueberry root systems moist, which is essential. Apply a 2- to 4-inch layer of woodchips, saw dust, or pine needles around the bush after planting.</li>
        \n<li>Blueberries need 1 to 2 inches of water per week.</li>
        \n<li>Drape netting over ripening blueberries, so that the birds won’t make away with the entire crop.</li>
        \n<li>One year after planting, apply 1 ounce of 10-10-10 fertilizer per bush in the spring at blooming time, and increase the rate by 1 ounce each year thereafter to a maximum of 8 ounces for mature bushes.</li>
        \n<li>Do not allow the bush to produce fruit for the first year or two after planting.</li>
        \n<li>Pinch back any blossoms developing on newly set plants to allow the energy to go to growth.</li>
    </string>
    <string name="pests_blueberries">
        <b><big>PESTS/DISEASES</big></b>\n
        \n<li>Birds</li>
        \n<li>Blueberry Maggot</li>
        \n<li>Powdery Mildew</li>
    </string>
    <string name="harvest_blueberries">
        <b><big>HARVEST/STORAGE</big></b>\n
        \n<li>Blueberries will be ready for picking in late July to mid August.</li>
        \n<li>Don’t rush to pick the berries as soon as they turn blue. Wait a couple days. When they are ready, they should fall off right into your hand.</li>
        \n<li>If you plant 2-year-old blueberry bushes, they should start to bear within a year or two. (Pick off any flowers that form the first year or two after planting, to allow the bush to become established.) Be aware that full production is reached after about 6 years.</li>
        \n<li>Blueberries are one of the easiest fruits to freeze.</li>
    </string>

    <string name="planting_mint">
        <b><big>PLANTING</big></b>\n
        \n<li>Mints are vigorous perennials that thrive in light soil with good drainage.</li>
        \n<li>Ideally, they prefer a moist but well-drained site, something like their native habitat along stream banks.</li>
        \n<li>Most will tolerate some shade, and the variegated types may require some protection from direct sun.</li>
        \n<li>For growing outdoors, plant one or two purchased plants (or one or two cuttings from a friend) about 2 feet apart in moist soil. One or two plants will easily cover the ground. Mint should grow to be 1 or 2 feet tall.</li>
        \n<li>For the best growth in confined areas such as containers, topdress plants with a thin layer of compost or organic fertilizer every few months. Aboveground pots will need winter protection in cold climates.</li>
        \n<li>In the garden, plant mint near cabbage and tomatoes.</li>
    </string>
    <string name="care_mint">
        <b><big>CARE</big></b>\n
        \n<li>Minimal care is needed for mint. For outdoor plants, use a light mulch. This will help keep the soil moist and keep the leaves clean.</li>
        \n<li>For indoor plants, be sure to water them regularly to keep the soil evenly moist.</li>
        \n<li>At first, mints develop into well-behaved–looking, bushy, upright clumps, but they soon set out to conquer new territory with horizontal runners and underground rhizomes. Unless you block the advance, a pert peppermint plant can turn into a sprawling 4-foot giant in just 1 year. It’s not the stuff of horror movies, however. Mints benefit from picking and pruning. They are shallow-rooted and easy to pull out, so there’s no reason to worry, as long as you provide physical barriers such as walls, walkways, or containers.</li>
    </string>
    <string name="pests_mint">
        <b><big>PESTS/DISEASES</big></b>\n
        \n<li>Powdery Mildew</li>
        \n<li>Rust</li>
        \n<li>Leaf spot</li>
        \n<li>Anthracnose</li>
        \n<li>Stem canker</li>
        \n<li>Mice dislike the smell of peppermint. Spread it liberally where you suspect the critters. Mint is also considered a deer-resistant plant.</li>
    </string>
    <string name="harvest_mint">
        <b><big>HARVEST/STORAGE</big></b>\n
        \n<li>Frequent harvesting is the key to keeping mint plants at their best. Young leaves have more flavor than old ones, and mint can be harvested as soon as it comes up in spring. Although fresh is best and sprigs keep for a few days in water, mint leaves can be frozen or air-dried in bunches.</li>
        \n<li>Right before flowering, cut the stems 1 inch from the ground. You can harvest one mint plant two or three times in one growing season.</li>
        \n<li>You can also just pick the leaves as you need them.</li>
        \n<li>You can grow the plants indoors for fresh leaves throughout the winter. If you want to dry them, it’s best to cut the leaves right before flowering. Store the dried leaves in an airtight container.</li>
    </string>
</resources>
